<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="Creation of the Report">
   <intro>
      <description>
         In this cheatsheet, we will see the basics of how to design a report. In the report creation process there are three main steps: creating a data source or a database connection used to fill the report, designing the report layout and running the report.
To keep things simple, this tutorial uses a sample database included in the installation of Jaspersoft Studio. The data to print is retrieved using an SQL query defined during the creation of the datasource.
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
         title="Start the Creation" dialog="true">
      <description>
         The first thing to do is start the wizard for the creation of a new report. To do this open the &quot;File&quot; menu and select &quot;New&quot; and then &quot;Jasper Report&quot;.
      </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="com.jaspersoft.studio.commands.ReportNewWizard"/>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Select the template">
      <description>
       In the first step of the wizard you can choose a template for the report, select the template &quot;Coffee&quot; and hit &quot;Next&quot;.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Define the report name and location">
      <description>
       You now must choose a location and a name for the report, for this parameters you can choose whatever you want, even the dafault values are good, then hit &quot;Next&quot;.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Creation of the main data adapter">
      <description>
       Now we must define a datasource, and we will use a database provided by default with JasperSoft Studio. For the field &quot;Data Adapter&quot; select from the drop down list the item <b>&quot;Sample DB - Database JDBC Connection&quot;</b>.
Now you must insert a query to define which data will be extracted from the database, use <b>&quot;select * from orders&quot;</b>, then hit &quot;Next&quot;.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Add the field to the Report">
      <description>
       Using the query provided in the previous step some fields are discovered and you can choose which ones add to the report. Double click on the field &quot;ORDERID&quot;, &quot;SHIPADDRESS&quot; and &quot;SHIPCITY&quot;. Then hit &quot;Next&quot;.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Finish the Wizard">
      <description>
       In the next step you can group the data, but we don&apos;t need the grouping at this time, so hit &quot;Next&quot; and then &quot;Finish&quot;.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Preview the Report">
      <description>
         Now you have your report with some fields into it. You can check if it is all right by click into the &quot;Preview&quot; tab. Doing this the report will be compiled and the result is shown.
      </description>
      <action pluginId="com.jaspersoft.studio.doc" class="com.jaspersoft.studio.doc.handlers.SwitchToPreviewHandler" required="false"/>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
